<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>



<!-- Remember, that top line is not really a tag. 
    It is a processing instruction that tells the computer that this is an XML file 
    and that it should be validated against a schema online at the TEI web site.-->

<TEI xml:id="stnic.201904.001.xml" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <!-- In the above line, change the xml:id to the id of your file: stnic.YYYYMM.001 
        (the 001 can be changed to 002, etc if we are encoding more than one piece from a particular month) -->

    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="a" type="main">Around the World with the Baseball Bugs.  A Collection of the Best Yarns and Humor of our Great Game</title>
                
            </titleStmt>


            <!-- The following section records information about who is publishing this file. -->
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2019</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</publisher>
                
                <date>2019</date>
                <availability>
                    <p>This file is freely distributed and
                        licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0
                        Unported License</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>

            <!-- A place to record additional info about the material -->
            <notesStmt>
                <note type="project">This file was produced for English 478/878: Digital Archives and Editions, Department of English, University of Nebraska-Lincoln, Spring 2019.</note>
            </notesStmt>


            <!-- This section describes the source, i.e., the document(s) you are encoding. -->

            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <!-- Insert title and date again here -->
                    <title level="a">Around the World with the Baseball Bugs.  A Collection of the Best Yarns and Humor of our Great Game</title>
                    <author>Jack Regan</author>
                    <author>Will E. Stahl</author>
                    <!-- Make an author or illustrator line for each one mentioned in the piece. -->
                    <publisher>J. Regan &amp; CO.</publisher>
                    <date>1910</date>
                    <!-- Note that @when allows a regularized form of the date -->
                  
                    <pubPlace>Chicago, Illinois</pubPlace>
                    <!--
                    <orgName>Westmill</orgName>
                    -->
                    <note>transcribed from sport collection, Special Collections, University Libraries, University of Nebraska-Lincoln. </note>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
       
        <!-- This part doesn't pertain to our book I believe
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <p/>
            </editorialDecl>
            
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <particDesc>
                <listPerson type="referenced">
                    <person xml:id="hwinsenberg">
                        <persName>Hans Wisenberg</persName>
                        <note>Was a prominent figure throughout the book, the protagonist of the issue.</note>
                    </person>
                </listPerson>
            </particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        -->

        <!-- This section records whose hands have been in the file. -->

        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="20190214">
                <name>Noah Loos</name>
                Encoded Header</change>
            <change when="20190418">
                <name>Brandon Heinz</name>
                Put revised header, put in translated text of book
            </change>
        </revisionDesc>
        
    </teiHeader>


    <!-- START ENCODING DOCUMENT HERE -->
    <text>
        <front>
            <pb facs="OG001.jpg"/>
            <pb facs="OG003.jpg"/>
            <pb facs="OG004.jpg"/>
            <div type="section">
                <pb n="6"/>
                <head>APOLOGY.</head>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
                <p>It being now the fashion for our professional 
                    athletes to either elevate the stage or raise the 
                    standard of journalism to their own ground and lofty 
                    standards, the authors of this book have presumed 
                    to confiscate some of their laurels—aud two-bit 
                    pieces, if we can get them—just to let the budding 
                    thespians and embryo journalists realize that they 
                    must expect legitimate competition in their respect- 
                    ive lines of endeavor, and we hope that such stars as 
                    Cristie, Tinker Joe, Muggsy, Jim, the Callahan, Mike, 
                    and others yet to be heard from now on the diam- 
                    ond, will not lead us too hard a race in the pursuit of 
                    the aforementioned two-bits. 
                    We should not feel that our duty had been ac- 
                    complished if we overlooked the roped arena, and 
                    pay our respects also to those doughty warriors who 
                    are now recognized as members of the pen pushers 
                    aggregation, viz. : the czar of Hegewisch, Ill., and 
                    the peerless J. J. J. Now get ready to smile. 
                    THE AUTHORS. </p>
            </div>
        </front>  
        <body>
            <pb facs="OG007.jpg"/>

            <div type="section">
                <pb n="7"/>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
                
                <head>A Shirt Front Protector.</head>
                               

                <p>"Charlie, dear," asked the fair maid at the ball 
                    park, " why does that man behind the hitter wear 
                    such a big bib? " 
                    " That," explained Charles, " is to keep his shirt- 
                    front from being mussed when the ball knocks out 
                    his front teeth."</p>
                
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <head>The Judge was on.</head>
                
                <p>For years and in various parts of the country efforts 
                    have been made to have baseball declared a public 
                    nuisance. 
                    All of these efforts have failed, and others will 
                    meet with as little success, according to a well-known 
                    Chicago attorney, who tells this story of a Judge, a 
                    brother lawyer and a state's attorney. 
                    " When the last of the post season games was 
                    being played an important case was before the court 
                    " The defense and opposing state's attorney were 
                    both rabid fans and wished to see the slugfest.</p>
                <pb n="8"/>
                <p>"During the noon recess it was agreed to ask for 
                    continuance until the next day, 
                    "When court convened in the afternoon, the de- 
                    ence stepped to the bar and said: 
                    "'May it please the court, I regret to have to ask 
                    a continuance. A witness has been called away by 
                    illness, and 1 do not see how I can proceed.' 
                    "'What has the state to say?' said the judge. 
                    "'While realizing the crowded condition of the 
                    docket, and the court's valuable time, the state feels 
                    it would be manifestly unfair to the defense to insist 
                    on proceeding,' said the state's attorney.' I suggest 
                    that the motion be favorably ruled on.' 
                    "'Allright,' said the court. ' Wait until I get my 
                    hat and i will go to the game with you.'"</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <head>The Youthful Goal.</head>
                <p>"I am sorry to have to tell you so, boys," said the 
                    pleasant-looking visitor who was addressing the 
                    Sunday-school class," but while there is only 
                    chance in a million that any one of you will ever be 
                    President of the United States, if you live up to your 
                    opportunities," eyeing keenly, for the effect, 
                    "some bright boy here jnay beconxe a world's cham- 
                    pion baseballist." 
                    And every boy sat up straight and began to listen</p>
                <pb n="9"/>
                <p>"I claim to be an original baseball fan, anyhow." 
                    "How so?" 
                    "I've never yelled 'O you Cobb,' or, let George do 
                    it,' when I was rooting."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="comic">
                <head>Some Warm Muffs.</head>
                <figure>
                <graphic url="OG009.jpg"/>
                </figure>
                <p>WIFEY—"Henry, is it cold out at the baseball grounds 
                    these days? " 
                    HUBBY—-"Cold? Why Helen, it is as hot as blazes. What 
                    in the name of Sam. Hill gave you Chat impression ? " 
                    WIFEY—" Why, the papers say tbe features of yesterday's 
                    game were several warm muffs.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <pb n="10"/>
                <p>Mrs. Newifewho inmpaticntly waiting for hubby. 
                    "Here it is five o'cloclc, and Frank not home, and 
                    mother expects us at six to dinner, I suppose that 
                    out of town buyer is detaining him as usual. Why 
                    can't they buy goods earlier in the day? " 
                    And hubby is sitting on a hard bench in the broil- 
                    ing sun, shouting himself hoarse. </p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>(Investor)*ITALICS*-"See here! You told me I'd surely
                    clear between five and six hundred dollars on that 
                    deal."
                    (Broker)*ITALICS*-"Well?"
                    (Investor)*ITALICS*-"Well, I cleared just eight dollars and
                    seventy-five cents on it."
                    (Broker)*ITALICS*-"Then you've got no kick. That's be- 
                    tween five dollars and six hundred dollars, isn't it?"</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"If you were awakened by a fire in the middle of 
                    the night, what would You think of saving first?" 
                    "My trousers."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"Bridget," said Mrs. Grouchy, "l don't like the 
                    looks of that man who called to see you last night."
                    "Well, Well," said Bridget, "aint it funny, ma'am?
                    He said the same about you."</p>
            </div>
            <div type="comic">
                <pb n="11"/>
                <figure>
                <graphic url="OG011.jpg"/>
                </figure>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
                <pb n="12"/>
                <head>The Batter's Soliloquy.</head>
                <head>DONALD DOUGLASS</head>
                <head>Ninth Inning, man on third, two gone, and score 2-2.</head> <!--NEEDS TO BE IN BOLD!-->
                <p>To wait, or not to wait,—that is the question: 
                    Whether 'tis nobler in this game to suffer 
                    The taunts and yells of the outrageous fans, 
                    Or to dodge the curves and drops of an erratic 
                    pitcher, 
                    And, by my coolness 'scape them? To wait—to 
                    walk,—
                    No more; and by a walk to say we stroll 
                    To first, and then be daring like Ty Cobb, 
                    And work the Double Steal,—'tis a consummation 
                    Devoutly to be wished. To walk—to steal— 
                    To steal. Perchance to score. Ay, there's the rub;— 
                    For in that Double Steal what chance may come 
                    When we have rattled the opposing pitcher, 
                    Must give us runs; there's the respect 
                    That makes a walk of so long life; 
                    For who would bear the yells and taunts of fans, 
                    The urnpire's wrong, the bleachers' contumely, 
                    "The pangs of disprized hope, the games delay, 
                    The insolence of gamins, and the spurns 
                    That one must take from the unknowing 
                    When he himself his fame might make</p>
                <pb n="13"/>
                <p>By a 2-bagger? Who would roastings bear, 
                    To grunt and swear under a weary game, 
                    But that the dread of somethiug after it, 
                    The Minor Leagues, from whose ranks 
                    No old time star returns, startles the mind;- 
                    And makes us rather bear those ills we have 
                    Than fly to others whence we ne'er return? 
                    These bleachers do make cowards of us all; 
                    And thus the fumble of a hard-hit grounder, 
                    Is yelled at by the bleacher mob, 
                    And, thus in places of great chance and moment, 
                    We all make bone-head plays that lose the game.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"Mistah Bones, do yo' beliebe in signs?" 
                    "No, sah, Mistah Brown; Ah don't beliebe in signs, 
                    De othah day Ah wuz feelin' sick, an' Ah saw a sign. 
                    Rubber Heels, 'an' Ah went home an' chewed a 
                    piece ob rubbah all day, an' de nex' day Ah wuz 
                    sicker dan eber. No, sah; Ah don't beliebe in no 
                    signs."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>(Gentleman)*ITALICS*—"Sambo, did you ever see the Catskil 
                    Mountains?" 
                    (Sambo)*ITALICS*—;"No, sah; but I seen 'em kill mice."</p>
                <pb n="14"/>
                <p>"What has become of the poor blind man who 
                    used to be on this corner?" "Oh, he wanted to see 
                    a ball game this afternoon, so I took his place." </p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"Here, you," said the conductor angrily; "you 
                    rang up a fare. Do that again and I'll put you off." 
                    The small man standing jammed in the middle of 
                    the car promptly rung up another fare. Thereupon 
                    the conductor projected him through the crowd and 
                    to the edge of the platform. 
                    "Thanks," said the little man. "I didn't see any 
                    other way to get out. Here's your dime."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Hotel clerk --"We have only one room left, sir, 
                    and the bed is only big enough for one. 
                    "Well, I subbose we'll haf to dake it, but I hate to 
                    haf my wife sleeb on der floor.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Country Editor— "I'm glad you brought these 
                    spring poems in early." 
                    Spring Poet—"Yes, sir?" 
                    Country Editor (putting them in the stove) 
                    "Yes, sir! Most spring poets wait till the weather 
                    gets too warm to use them."</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <pb n="15"/>
                <p>"Your husband's very busy these times, Mrs.Grady."
                    "Yis! he uts in so much time in the day blath-
                    ering pennants, he have to work nights." </p>
            </div>
            <div type="comic">
                <head>Reminiscences.</head>
                <figure>
                <graphic url="OG015.jpg"/>
                </figure>
                <p>FIRST PARROT BUG—"Where did you cop out all that 
                    bad language?"
                    SECOND DITTO—"Sh! listen. My ex-boss thought he 
                    understood the base ball game."</p>
            </div>
            <div type="comic">
                <pb n="16"/>
                <head>To the Ball Grounds or Bust.</head>
                
                <figure>
                <graphic url="OG016.jpg"/>
                </figure>
                <p>Hooligan— "Oi do be wondherin' how th' number 
                    av min in church compare wid thi wimmin?" 
                    Hinessy— "About th' same as th' wimmin com- 
                    pare wid th' min in th' pinitinchery"</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <pb n="17"/>
                <p>"I tell you, sir, kissing the hand that smites you is
                    nothing to what I saw in the hotel this morning."
                    "What was that?"
                    "The porter blacking the boots that had kicked
                    him last night."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Magistrate (sternly)— "Didn't I tell you the last
                    time you were here I never wanted you to come be- 
                    fore me again ?" 
                    Prisoner— "Yes, sir; but I couldn't make the 
                    policeman believe it."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"This business of giving people a lot of straps to 
                    hang on to in the cars is all wrong!" exclaimed the 
                    indignant citizen. 
                    "That's right," answered Mr. Dustin Stax, with 
                    sudden interest;"the public ought to be made to 
                    furnish its own straps."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"Good morning, ma'am," said Willie, doffing his 
                    cap. 
                    "Why! What a polite little boy!" exclaimed Miss 
                    Passay."Do you always take off your cap like that 
                    to ladies?"
                    "No'm; only to old ladies."</p>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
                <pb n="18"/>
                <head>Why "Pug" Dugan called McCarty Out.</head>
                <p>No wonder that "Pug" Dugan
                    Wore a perpetual scowl,
                    No wonder that unto him
                    Life's skies seemed ever foul!
                    For "Pug" a "has-been" pitcher,
                    Now held an umpire's job,
                    And heard himself called daily:
                    "Rube,""robber,""soak" and "slob"
                    "Pug" brooded o'er his troubles,
                    The scowling, howling fans, 
                    The bickering, blustering players,
                    The captains with their "damns!"
                    He swore that he no longer
                    His troubles would endure,
                    And planned a way to end them
                    That would be swift and sure!
                    That day, the Wolves, the home team, 
                    The Bisons were to play.
                    The whole of Wolfburg journeyed
                    To see their heroes play.
                    The Bisons led the leagues now, 
                    But the Wolves held second place,
                    And if they beat the Bisons
                    The wolves would lead the race.</p>
                <pb n="19"/>
                <p>Through six exciting innings 
                    "Pug's" umpiring was good; 
                    No jeers carne from thc rooters, 
                    No player him withstood. 
                    Then came the seventh inning 
                    (The fierce game still a tie), 
                    And "Pug" unto himself said, 
                    "The time arrives to die!" 
                    McCarthy, of the home team, 
                    The bison's twirler faced. 
                    The first ball pitched he clouted; 
                    In vain the fielder chased.
                    McCarthy, made the circuit 
                    While the joy-crazed multitude 
                    Yelled "Rah for Dan McCarthy! 
                    We're one run to the good! 
                    But in that merry moment 
                    The umpire raised his hand. 
                    A hush fell on the ball-field, 
                    on bleacher, box and stand. 
                    "Hold on there!""Pug" spake loudly, 
                    "D'ye think my eyes were shut? 
                    McCarthy's out! The first bag 
                    By a full yard he cut!</p>
                <pb n="20"/>
                <p>The bleachers gave a war-whoop! 
                    The grandstand joined its roar!
                    The scribes within the press-box,
                    Bawled loudly for "Pug's" gore!
                    But ere their was wrath vented,
                    McCarthy grabbed the bat 
                    That knocked that honest homer,
                    And laid the umpire flat. 
                    Up rushed the other Wolves then, 
                    Their heels in him they dug, 
                    And the punches they rained on him 
                    Made jelly out of "Pug!" 
                    Up came the maddened rooters, 
                    A fierce, blood-thirsty swarm, 
                    They made the umpire shapeless 
                    By stamping on his form ! 
                    Cried police, judges, preacher: 
                    "Leave not a shred of him!" 
                    Save Bisonburg, the land cried:
                    "He earned it! Devil's limb!" 
                    They buried "Pug," unprayed-for, 
                    In marshy, worthless land, 
                    And no one ever dreamed that he 
                    Just such a death had planned, 
                    —D.M. HENDERSON, Jr.</p>           
                
            </div>
            <div type="comic">
                <pb n="21"/>
                <head>The Beginning of our Trouble</head>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="OG021.jpg"/>
                    <p>Gimme a quick shave
                        Right here Sir Yessir</p>
                    
                </figure>
                <head>A Wet Finish</head>
                <p>Now if the Tigers lose two and New York two and- well
                    SAY DO I GET A SHAVE SAY</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <pb n="22"/>
                <head>The Three Bats.</head>
                <p>     One of the foremost players in the American 
                    league is an ardent lecturer on temperance among 
                    his fellow-players. A story that has been going the 
                    rounds regarding the antics of an inebriated bats. 
                    man is said to have originated with him. Here it is: 
                    "A friend who had been celebrating, reported one 
                    afternoon in such shape that he could barely walk 
                    straight. When he went to bat he complained to 
                    the umpire tha the saw three bats and three balls. 
                    " Take the middle bat and hit the middle ball,' 
                    he was advised. 
                    He took three vigorous swings and was struck 
                    out. 
                    "'Why didn't you do as I suggested?' asked the 
                    umpire. 
                    "'I did,' said the player, 'but I hit with the out- 
                    side of the bat, and that's why I missed.'"</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"I'm gunning for railroads," announced the trust- 
                buster. 
                "Then me," whispered the near-humor- 
                ist. I can show you some of their tracks.</p>
            <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Charity covers a multitude of skins.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="comic">
                <pb n="23"/>
                <head>Reading the Dope on the way to the Grounds.</head>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="OG023.jpg"/>
                </figure>
                <p>"I teach my parrot only short words." 
                    "Do you? Now, I should think that parrots were 
                    better adapted to learning polysyllables."</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <pb n="24"/>
                <p>Wanted. A short-stop to catch a high ball. Scotch
                    preferred</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Brown-"Yes,sir; Doctor Jones cured me."
                Minister-"No, my friend; Providence cured
                you, not the doctor."
                Brown-"Well maybe he did, but the doctor will charge for it.',</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"She's a corker!" 
                    "Who?" 
                    "Why, that girl who works down at the bottle 
                    factory."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Jessica-"When the judge asked you how old 
                    you were, what did you say?" 
                    Margery-"I told him if he were a good judge he 
                    wouldn't ask."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Sooner Nott - "De best day's work I ever done in 
                    me life wuz de day I got married." 
                    Howitt Waus-"How wuz dat?" 
                    Sooner Nott-"I worked fadder-in-law fer 
                    five dollars ter pay de minister an' hung up de min- 
                    ister."</p>
            </div>
            <div type="comic">
                <pb n="25"/>
                <head>Back from the Grounds.  Favorite Losers.</head>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="OG025.jpg"/>
                </figure>
                <p>"Algy, why does the catcher wear that muzzle?" 
                    "To prevent him from biting the batsman my 
                    dear."</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <pb n="26"/>
                <head>A Good Scheme.</head>
                <p>Some ball players shirk in their work just as lazy 
                    men do in factories or in other branches of labor, 
                    according to an Eastern magnate. 
                    Many ingenious excuses to obtain holidays have 
                    been framed up, but we used to have a fellow who 
                    wasn't satisfied with verbal excuses, but who actual- 
                    ly disabled himself. He was expert at bunting, and 
                    could judge a pitched ball so closely that he could 
                    hit with any part of his bat. One day he was acci- 
                    dentally hit on the index finger of his right hand, 
                    the digit being crushed so that he was unfit for duty 
                    for two weeks. Well, after that he used to smash a 
                    finger regularly, varying the trick occasionally by 
                    letting the ball hit his second finger. 
                    "As a result of his conniving, he played only thir- 
                    ty garnes that season, and drew full pay. He 
                    became known as the champion hard luck' player."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"Does your wife object to late dinners?" 
                    "It all depends," said Mr. Meekton, "on whether
                    the cause is a baseball game or manitee."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>The worst about marrying for money is it so
                    often turns out to be counterfeit.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <pb n="27"/>
                <head>When Does the Game start.</head>
                <p>A Detroit fan tells a story of a girl whom he took 
                    to see a game in that city. 
                    "She told me she knew all about the game, and 
                    when the players got on the field before the game 
                    to 'warm up,' she asked me what they were doing. 
                    I told her they were practicing. 
                    "The game started and she never uttered a word 
                    until about the seventh inning, when she leaned 
                    over to me and said:'say, Grover, when are they 
                    going to start the game?'"</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
                <head>"Een Right."</head>
                <p>  Say, boss, you bet, 
                    My boy Sylves, 
                    He joosta got een right: 
                    No work all day, 
                    But mak mooch pay, 
                    Een dis-a prize a-fight. 
                    Dat's grand-a game, 
                    No work, joost train, 
                    Den malc da swell a fight ; 
                    You mak da bet 
                    On wat I set— 
                    My boy, he ees een right.</p>
                <pb n="28"/>
                <p>Wen first he train
                    For dat-a game
                    He use I-taly name;
                    Some fren, mooch wise,
                    Open hees eyes
                    To hav da Irish name. 
                    So Pasty Burke, da vicious Turk,
                    Dat's wat he name Sylves,
                    Who win tree fight,
                    All een one night;
                    you bet, I swell da ches!
                    I hav to leave da shoemake shop
                    To be on dees ringside
                    To see dat no
                    Great-a beeg horseshoe
                    in boxing glove he hide.
                    It seem it mak a deefrance now
                    Between me an da cop;
                    Nowday he yell,
                    "Hop-a you feel well,"
                    Before, "Hallo, you wop!"</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>                
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"Those fable bugs is allright, but I know lots of 
                    pitchers who got broke without going to a well."</p>
            </div>
            <div type="comic">
                <pb n="29"/>
                <head>The Home Plate.</head>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="OG029.jpg"/>
                </figure>
                <p>Mrs. Black-"Yo' husband doan' take no intrest in
                    baseball, do he, Mrs. Brown? Now my husband am always 
                    talkin' about the home plates."
                    Mrs. Brown-"Huh! De on'y plate ma husban' talks of am de dinner plate."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Reporter-"I suppose you don't know what the 
                senator thinks about this tariff-reform business?"
                Senator's Private Secretary-"No; no more than
                you do. I only know what he says about it."</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <pb n="30"/>
                <head>A Good-Natured Josh.</head>
                <p>  A Southern League player tells a yarn on a mem-
                    ber of the Boston Americans.
                    "The beanerite at the time was playing amateur
                    ball in a little Texas town called Hubbard City, and
                    Shelton, a great kidder, was managing Temple, Tex.
                    He wanted a pitcher and the S.L man told him of 
                    the Boston guy. Shelton wired him and the kid came
                    on the first train. Next day he was put in the box
                    and the life hammered out of him, the opponents
                    making nineteen hits in five innings. In that inning
                    the Boston party asked Shelton what he thought of 
                    his work. Shelton smiled, saying: "Young man, 
                    you are doing splendid. They've not made a single
                    off of you yet; although they have made a nineteen 
                    hits- all doubles, triples and homers." Bean eater
                    never tumbled.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <head>Post Mortem Games.</head>
                <p>  During the post-season series of last year, a bug 
                    with a dediced Teutonic accent approached the Vice-
                    President of a Chicago bank, who is also a rabid
                    bug, and vociferously shouted to the V.P.: "Say,
                    who is vat is going to vin dose post-mortem games
                    ha?" Can you beat it?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="comic">
                <pb n="31"/>
                <head>Imitation of an Orator Reciting "Casey at the Bat."</head>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="OG031.jpg"/>
                </figure>
                <p>De Style-"Was that a drinking-song the sop-
                    rano just sang?"
                    Gunbusta-"Why, no. What makes you ask that?"
                    De style- There were so many high bawls in it."</p>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
                <pb n="32"/>
                <head>Just Baseball.</head>
                <p>The honey of spring was in the air
                    The day was one for joy,
                    But he sat at his desk and didn't care
                    And he growled at the office boy.
                    
                    He nursed a big grouch--the world looked dark-
                    He only grumbled and frowned; 
                    He grabbed his hat and went to the park 
                    To see the home team downed.
                    
                    For eight innings he sat—not a feeling of pride, 
                    Though the game was close and fast;— 
                    He looked for defeat, though the game was tied 
                    When they took the field for the last.
                    
                    Three men got on bases, chances looked slim,
                    A score seemed as sure as fate.
                    He muttered a prayer, and his smile was grim 
                    As the batter strode to the plate.
                    
                    The pitcher gazed, his arm held high, 
                    And smiling, tossed his head. 
                    The batter swung-the rooters sighted 
                    As the ball for the outfield sped.</p>
                <pb n="33"/>
                <p>
                    But into the air like a bolt from a gun
                    Went the shortstop and saved the day.
                    His eye was true- and there was no run,
                    For he pulled off a triple play.
                    
                    The man with the grouch jumped up on his feet 
                    And hurled his hat at the sun, 
                    And hc whooped and roared and stamped his feet 
                    Whcn the home boys made a run.
                    
                    Happy and glad he went on his way 
                    His grouch gone beyond re-call, 
                    And his happiness lasted for many a day,— 
                    Yes, baseball's the best game of all.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Mistress—"Jane, I saw the milkman kiss you this 
                    morninge In the future I will take the milk in.' 
                    Jane-"Twouldn't be no use, mum. He's promis-
                    ed never to kiss anybody but me."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>First Fan—"How did the team make out today?" 
                    Second Fan—"Same as usual." 
                    First Fan—"How's that?  
                    Second Fan—"Three men to an inning."</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <pb n="34"/>
                <head>Some Hots Liners.</head>
                <p>Have you ever been seated low, when a husky 
                    cop with shoulders like a buffalo, planted his hulk 
                    in front of you and got interested in the field?</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>When is a ball player like a jeweler? 
                    When he is on the diamond</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"Frank Chance once slept in the bed you were in 
                    last night,"said the enthusiastic clerk bug at the 
                    hotel. 
                    "That's more than I could do," replied the weary 
                    knight of the grip.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Root, and the world roots with you
                    Beef, and you beef alone 
                    For the umpire bold, has no friends we are told 
                    And we'll skin him down to the bone</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>If a batsman is a good "soaker" what would you
                    call a booze-fighter?</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"If there is going to be any running in thsi game,
                    I'm going to do it," said water to the wagon.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="comic">
                <pb n="35"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="OG035.jpg"/>
                    <p>WINKs-"There goes a man whose  
                        inventive genius has been a boon to  
                        base ballists." 
                        BINKS—Invented a new rule, eh?"
                        WINKS-"Oh, no! He invented a  
                        cuss word to fit any angle that may 
                        arise in the game."</p>
                </figure>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <head>Caught out.</head>
                <p>"Won't you take 
                    me to a ball game 
                    when the season 
                    opens?" inuired
                    little brother. 
                    "I never go to 
                    ball games," said 
                    Mr. Softleigh. 
                    "I thought you 
                    was a player. Ma
                    told Sis you was a 
                    good catch.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <head>Bad for Charlie</head>
                <p>"What is that
                    makes ball games
                    so bad for the
                    health?" asks Mrs.
                    Brown
                    "Bad for the health. What do you mean?" 
                    "Why every time Charlie comes home from the 
                    ball game, hey says there's something rotten with
                    his system."</p>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
                <pb n="36"/>
                <head>The Umpire.</head>
                <p>Of all the inscrutable creatures there be 
                    A top of the earth or below in the sea. 
                    The ump is the beatenest being, sure, He 
                    Consorteth apart in mystery. 
                    His integument's blue, there's a pad on his chest, 
                    His frontal is masked and his features unguessed; 
                    On his mind is a cap, and—well, as for the rest 
                    Whatever it be, its the subject of jest. 
                    Oh, the ump's a pariah—the other team's tool 
                    He bawls out decisions and balls up each rule; 
                    He sure gets the vote 
                    As the champion goat; 
                    There is never a crowd to be in the same boat, 
                    The umps get their bumps, but this to b 
                    There is balm (vernal plasters) in Gilead. 
                    The ump is a seer who was born with a cad; 
                    The ump is a Solomon—under a pall ; 
                    One time he's the Saint, and the nest 
                    The ump's like the place Caesar tells of-all Gaul.</p>
                <pb n="37"/>
                <p>He's a modern Bozzais—shouts "Strike!" with clan 
                    (In the sumnler no doubt he likes batters to fan), 
                    And if the armed foe should rebel at the plan 
                    It's the bench quick for him and proscription by 
                    Ban. 
                    Oh, the ump is a monarch, a pocket size Czar;
                    He could even give points in that line to T.R. 
                    He is always emphatic 
                    And often erratic; 
                    The alienists say he has dust in his attic. 
                    But brush him a bit and proceedings he stops— 
                    And then strides from the field midst a cordon 
                    cops.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>A young man of Boston, who had failed to pay 
                    his laundry bill, endeavored to turn his Chinaman
                    aside from inquiry by an attack upon the celestial's
                    manner of speech. "Why do you say 'Fliday,'
                    John?" he asked.
                    "Say Fliday because I mean Fliday," replied
                    John Stoutly. "No say Fliday, and mean maybe
                    week after nex,'like 'Melican man."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>All the world loves a lover and a ball player.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
                <pb n="38"/>
                <head>Willie's Brother's Demise.</head>
                <p>Willie was an office boy,
                    Willie was a fan;
                    Willie knew more about baseball
                    Than many an older man.
                    Wille said his brother
                    Was sick as a man could be,
                    And "Please could he get off to day
                    To bear bim companee?" 
                    "You may," the boss said gently,
                    Gazing at Willie the while,
                    And Willie's look as he stood there
                    Was totally free from guile.
                    His head bowed low with sorrow,
                    He slowly went outside,
                    While gloom hung over the office,
                    And the secretary cried.
                    Next day he showed up at the office,
                    With a frown as black as night;
                    The Boss, with kindly manner,
                    Inquired if all was not right.</p>
                <pb n="39"/>
                <p>"Not on your life," said Willie, 
                    Forgetting himself in his rage, 
                    Which was rather improper of Willie, 
                    Considering he wasn't of age, 
                    "Oh, tell me, Willie, tell me," 
                    The gentle Boss then cried; 
                    "Your brother—is he safe at home ? 
                    Or has the poor chap died ? " 
                    "I should say he wasn't safe at home 
                    (There was venom in every word), 
                    "In the end of the ninth—de score a tie— 
                    The sucker DIED AT THIRD!"</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Owner-"You see this is a convertible flat." 
                    Househunter-"Yes, I know. Turkish bath in sum- 
                    mer and refrigerator in winter."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Professional wanderer-"Sonny, is this here 
                    town one o' them local-option towns?" 
                    Boy—"Yes, sir; I guess so, sir. You can get it 
                    either at the drug store or the grocery."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Mr. Didymus-Ah, Miss Anacosta, I was at the 
                    game Yesterday and saw you at a distance. 
                    "Yes; I trust I shall see you there again"</p>
                <pb n="40"/>
                <p>"Well, what chances do the Naps stand for the
                    pennant this year?"
                    Don't know."
                    "What? Haven't you any dope on it?"
                    Nope. My barber is a deaf mute."-</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
                <p>In this time of rising prices
                    Butt in quick and be a goat.
                    Be a beefer, get the money
                    or a rooter minus coat.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
                <p>Now, here's a fact, in jest of course,
                    Yet not a cause for laughter;
                    Who chews the rag through all this life,
                    Will surely smoke hereafter.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Mrs. Kawler-"Your husband has some particu-
                    lar bent, hasn't he?"
                    Mrs. Crossway-"Yes; you know as well as I do 
                    that he's dreadfully hump shouldered, but I don't
                    think it's a bit nice of you to mention it."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"Never pretend that you know it all, Johnny."
                    counseled Mrs.Lapsling. "There is such a thing as 
                    being too saponaceous."</p>
            </div>
            <div type="comic">
                <pb n="41"/>
                <figure>
                <head>A Proud Fan exhibiting his Cub.</head>
                <graphic url="OG041.jpg"/>
                    <p>"He was very unpopular before the last ball 
                        game, but after he had three runs and won tlv 
                        game he had many friends.' 
                        "Ah! I suppose he made friends by the score."</p>
                </figure>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <pb n="42"/>
                <head>How it is Done at Washington</head>
                <p>"Old Nick" Young, as his friends call him, the
                    veteran ex-president of the national Baseball
                    League, and one of the most faithful as well as best
                    natured of "fans" on the continent, maintains a box
                    at the Washington ball park, for the purpose, one
                    might suppose, of inviting his friends to witness the
                    slaughter of the "Senators" by the various visiting
                    teams. Nick is notably fond of young people, and
                    has an appreciative eye for pretty girls, a bevy of 
                    whom always may be seen occupying the front
                    seats in his choicely located box. The young ladies
                    have to pay for this privilege, however, by listening
                    to the funny stories of the veteran, who by the
                    way, is old enough to be the grandfather of great
                    grandfather of most of them. Here is young's
                    latest:
                    "I was down in South Carolina, a few days ago,
                    in  the town of Greenville. You know i nver can
                    pass up a ball game, and when I learned that there
                    was a double-header on between Greenville and her
                    greatest rival, Spartanburg, why it was to me to the
                    park! Well the place was packed, and the only 
                    seats to be had were in the bleachers. that South
                    Carolina sun is a red hot brand, and during the</p>
                <pb n="43"/>
                <p>game a spectator toppled over with sunstroke. At 
                    the request of a physician a telegrapher at the park
                    ticked to the operator up town and asked him 
                    to send down the ambulance. Just a little while
                    after this excitement had passed two partisans of
                    the rival towns began mixing blows with their argu-
                    ments. The officer on duty yanked them out of
                    their seats and called to the operator: 
                    "Wire the chief to send out the patrol wagon!'"
                    "The obliging operator hustled the message over
                    the wire.
                    "'Sure!' ticked back the man. 'When do you
                    want the fire department?'"</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Gunner: Poor chap! There is always a mob 
                    howling for his scalp.
                    Guyer: Well, in the baseball season he's an
                    umpire.
                    Guyer: O, he's not so badly off. He has peace
                    in the winter.
                    Gunner: No, in the winter he is complaint clerk
                    in the gas office.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>A runner is like a lunatic, he's "off his base."</p>
            </div>
            <div type="comic">
                <pb n="44"/>
                <figure>
                    <head>What did we do to that Pennant?</head>
                    <graphic url="OG044.jpg"/>
                    <p>Oh! What a headache!</p>
                </figure>
            </div>
            <div type="section ">
                <p>Two young lawyers were lunching at the Union
                    League the other day, when one of them mentioned
                    a mutual acquaintance.
                    "Brown is a good fellow, no doubt," said the
                    other,"he never appealed to me."
                    "I suppose he knew it wouldn't be any use,"mum-
                    mered Brown's friend, politely: "you are usually
                    broke."</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <pb n="45"/>
                <head>Some Don't for the Ball Fan.</head>
                <p>Don't leave until the game is over, the last lap 
                    has often won the game. 
                    Don't blackguard the "ump," he is better posted
                    than you are, and just as honest.
                    Don't shout your lungs away, you'll need them in 
                    your business. 
                    Don't think you have an exclusive line on the 
                    dope, your neighbor may be as well posted as you. 
                    Don't get familiar with players names while they 
                    are on the field, they might not recognize you, 
                    Don't tell your neighbor the home team might 
                    have won if they had taken your shouts as good 
                    horse sense, the manager gives advice.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Frank Bancroft, president of the Cincin- 
                    nati Baseball Club, was manager of the minor 
                    league, he tried out a recruit one day and the 
                    youngster's showing was far from the necessary 
                    e game the player came to 
                    Bancroft and said:
                    "Well, I was away off to-day, but-"
                    "Yes," interrupted Bancroft, "and you will be
                    farther off to-morrow," and he released him forth-
                    with.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
                <pb n="46"/>
                <head>Ye Ancienct Manageer.</head>
                <p>The baseball Fan sat on a stone, 
                    He could not choose but hear,
                    And then spake on that hopeful man— 
                    The Bright-Eyed Manageer.
                    
                    "Although it's early, it would seem," 
                    The modest manager will say, x
                    "We have the very finest team 
                    The diamond's seen in many a day. 
                    Yes, I am feeling pretty gay, 
                    And you can take my little steer 
                    That we will put 'em all away— 
                    We ought to get the flag this year.
                    
                    "Our staff of pitchers is supreme; 
                    Our catcher is a veteran gray; 
                    Our fielders are the very cream— 
                    The finest in the U. S. A. 
                    We'll take the lead in early May 
                    And keep it till the end is here; 
                    We'll get in front and there we'll stay— 
                    We ought to get the flag this year.
                    
                    "Yes, you can bet your last centime
                    The rest'll know there's been a fray</p>
                <pb n="47"/>
                <p>When we get through, and that's no dream.
                    Why, if you'd seen those fellows play
                    In practice you'd just yell 'Hooray!' 
                    That pennant's on the chandelier—— 
                    The rest we simply overlay— 
                    We ought to get the flag this year."
                    L'ENVOI 
                    Pin on thy premature bouquet, 
                    O Prophet of the Leather Sphere, 
                    We feel, what time we hope and pray, 
                    We ought to get the flag this year.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"Yes," explained the summer girl "I had nine
                    chances and accepted eight of them." 
                    "How about the other?"
                    "I found afterward that he was the most eligible 
                    of them all." 
                    "Too bad." 
                    "Yes; I suppose I must be charged with an error."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Simon Shucks—Ikarius is a pretty high up man.
                    Col. Cobb—Thirty-third degree?
                    "Higher'n that—ary-plane."</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <pb n="48"/>
                <head>Why is this?</head>
                <p>In looking over the list of names comprising the
                    American and National Leagues we fail to discover
                    any of those well worn Semitic cognomens, such as 
                    Moses, Abraham, Ikey, Solomon, Aaron, etc., or 
                    the tribe of numerous "Skys."  Something wrong.
                    Is the work too arduous?</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Tom—"Did you know that Harry was hurt on 
                    the belt line last night?"
                    Dick—"Is that so.  Was he hurt much?"
                    Tom—"No, only a scratch on the finger."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
                
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Browne—"Say, do you know that I think you 
                    would make a fine ball player Jonesy?" 
                    Jones (who has a hasty temper)—"What makes
                    you think that?" 
                    Browne—"Why, just because you go up in the
                    air so easily."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Where did Murphy go after the ball game?"
                    "Call up the hospital."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"Who is your favorite baseball player jags?"
                    "My boy at College, sir!"</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <pb n="49"/>
                <head>Let the Government do it.</head>
                <p>The Government at Washington is now furnishing 
                    an essay on the preparation of food for the masses. 
                    Why cannot we fans petition them to furnish base- 
                    ball literature? It is just as important to the youth- 
                    ful mind, as it is to tell Mamma how to make hash.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
                <head>Just Averages.</head>
                <p>The Winter league is here again, and in his native 
                    town
                    The hero of a thousand games has quietly settled
                    down.
                    Spike Mulligan, the shotstop brave, who led the 
                    league in hitting,
                    And drew one thousand bones a month for tending 
                    to his knitting, 
                    Is working in the corner store, slaving to beat the
                    band,
                    And drawing fifteen seeds a month for selling sug-
                    ared sand.
                    O'Halloran, the pitcher, who was certainly a hum-
                    mer,
                    And got a prince's ransom for the work he did last
                    summer,
                    Is keeping books this winter for a shop that deals
                    in buckets,</p>
                <pb n="50"/>
                <p>And getting for the same each month as much as
                    twenty ducats.
                    McGonnigal, the fielder fleet, who hit like mad all
                    season,
                    And got a monthly envelope that seemed beyond
                    all reason,
                    Is driving team in Grangerville, and adding to his 
                    hoard 
                    By drawing down a salary of five aweek and board. 
                    McGinn the famous backstop, who could throw so 
                    well to bases, 
                    And who received last season fifty-seven hundred 
                    aces, 
                    Is throwing cordwood on a sled, far from the root-
                    ers' gaze, 
                    And getting eighteen dollars cash for every thirty
                    days. 
                    The Winter league is here again, and in his native
                    town 
                    The hero of a thousand games has quietly settled 
                    down.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Medical Understudy--Dr. Allwise, have you
                    decided whether or not Mr. Speckham has appendi-
                    citis?  You said you were going to read up on the
                    case.
                    Dr. Allwise--Glad you reminded me of that.
                    Hand me that last Bradstreet's.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="comic">
                <pb n="51"/>
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="OG051.jpg"/>
                    <p>"I Will."--Apologies to Miss Chicago.</p>
                </figure>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
                <pb n="52"/>
                <head>Like Kellie Did.</head>
                <p>Bill Sweeney was a backstop on the mooted Bug-
                    ville team:
                    At winging down to second base Bill Sweeney was
                    a dream; 
                    The rooters used to swear by him, he their joy
                    and pride,
                    Until he tried to emulate the famous "Kelley
                    slide." 
                    For Bill had seen this Kelley steal base after base
                    and slide, 
                    Had noted carefully his walk, his manner, and his 
                    stride; 
                    And Sweeney wished a thousand ways each time
                    the rooters cried 
                    They'd change the yell from Kelley and would
                    screech: "Slide, Sweeney, slide!"
                    But Kelley was a player with a wondrous burst of
                    speed, 
                    While Sweeney had a cracking whip but great 
                    speed seemed to need; 
                    And though he copied Kelley's style, when pos-
                    ible, and slid. 
                    The fans yelled: "Sweeney stole a base!  He 
                    did?--Like Kelley did!" 
                    For Sweeney was a moving van whene'er he reach-
                    ed a bag,
                    And when he tried to steal his feet would tangle 
                    up and lag;</p>
                <pb n="53"/>
                <p>And when he'd start the fans would yelp together 
                    as a man: 
                    "O, Sweeney, he can steal a base! He can?—Like 
                    Kelley can!" 
                    Now, Sweeney was bullheaded, and he didn't seem 
                    to know 
                    He hadn't speed enough to beat the slowest kind 
                    of throw. 
                    But Sweeney said that Kelley stole a base each 
                    time he slid,
                    And so, he'd keep on trying till he stole—like
                    Kelley did! 
                    The ninth round came; the visitors had tied the 
                    single score;
                    The side retired, the home boys came to bat amid 
                    a roar.
                    Bill opened with a double and was booted down to 
                    third;
                    Then rose the loudest rooting, Sweeney swore, he
                    ever heard.
                    The next two died ere reaching first, and Bill was
                    held on third.
                    Up stepped the heavy sticker of the team, a clout-
                    in bird.
                    But while Bill pawed the ground at third, out yelled
                    a zealous fan:
                    "O, Bill can steal home base and win! He can?
                    Like Kelley can!"</p>
                <pb n="54"/>
                <p>Bill heard!  Before his eyes there flashed a swift
                    and livid flame!
                    At last the time was come to act—immortalize his
                    name!
                    His daily practice had improved his speed—he'd
                    sure make good! 
                    He now was fleet as Kelley, and could steal—like
                    Kelley could! 
                    And then, e'en while the pitcher held the ball,
                    Bill sprang from third! 
                    "Go back, you bonehead!"  cried the boss, but
                    Sweeney never heard 
                    A hush fell on the multitude—a silence deep, pro- 
                    found, 
                    While Bill dived to the earth and plowed up twenty 
                    feet of ground. 
                    In Bugville's potter's field to-day there is a little
                    plot, 
                    And o'er it stands a painted board which marks 
                    Bill's resting spot; 
                    And those who run may read these words: "At 
                    last the fans are rid 
                    of Sweeney, who stole home and Won! He did?
                    —Like Kelley did!"</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Clubman—Waiter, do you know what water is?
                    Waiter—Savin' yer prisince, but ye're the third
                    gintleman this day that's shown his ignorance of 
                    that same biverage.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="comic">
                <pb n="55"/>
                <figure>
                    <head>Idle thoughts of the Season's end.</head>
                    <graphic url="OG055.jpg"/>                    
                </figure>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <head>A Vain Hope.</head>
                <p>A ball player who be- 
                    tween times defends di-
                    vorce suits, had a finger 
                    badly hurt when he was
                    new at the game, and a
                    doctor was called in to 
                    attend to it. The sur- 
                    geon was cheerful, and 
                    insisted that after a lit- 
                    tle rest the finger would 
                    be as good as ever. 
                    "Sure of that?" said 
                    the b. p. 
                    "Sure as can be," said 
                    the doc. 
                    "Will I be able to play 
                    the piano?"
                    "Certainly."
                    "I'm mighty glad of that," answered the twirler, 
                    "I have tried to play it for ten years, and haven't 
                    struck a tune yet."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Cheer up! A good loser is more to be admired
                    than a poor winner.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <pb n="58"/>
                <p>Friends and relatives reported missing will prob- 
                    ably be found at the gate, waiting for an over- 
                    crowded car.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Young Lawyer—Shake, Gladys. I have a case at 
                    last. A rascal who forged a lot of paper has retain-
                    ed me.
                    Young Wife—How good of him! Ask him 
                    dinner.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>It is so easy to understand the day after just why 
                    the game went that way that we almost forgive the 
                    man who told us so.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"Funny! The multimillionaire always signs his 
                    letters 'In haste.'"
                    "You bet he is in haste. There is a subpoena 
                    server right on his trail."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
                    
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Minister—Have you anything to regret, brother?
                    Old Soak—Nope!  I ain't leaving a cent.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Rastus' Report by Phone—De Rabbitfoots was
                    lammin' de Roosters foh a finish when de umpiah
                    called "Foul." Bo'f nines clim' de fence and looked 
                    foh de chicken.  Nothin' mo' doin' today.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <pb n="59"/>
                <p>"That man on the bleachers seems to be light in 
                    the upper story." 
                    "You mean the chap with the lantern jaws."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Baseball Reporter (meeting a senator unexpect- 
                    edly at his house)—I came to get the ladies' gowns. 
                    Senator (glancing into the drawing room at the 
                    exhibition of bare shoulders)—They certainly seem 
                    to need them.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Butt— My finances have about reached the point 
                    of saturation. 
                    Rutt—Reached the point of what? 
                    Butt—The point where something will have to be 
                    soaked.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"Why do you spank your dear children?" 
                    "So I can get palm red without going to a 
                    fortune teller."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"If I were a king," said the weary magnate, "I'd 
                    have a field of my own and have the first man who 
                    asked for a pass hanged."
                    "Good idea," replied the manager.  In that case
                    we could truthfully say, "free list entirely suspend-
                    ed.'"</p>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
                <pb n="60"/>
                <head>The First Official Line-Up.</head>
                <p>Eve stole first, and Adam second;
                    Ruth in the field won fame. 
                    Goliath was struck out by David, 
                    And Abel made a base hit on Cain. 
                    The prodigal son made one home run, 
                    And Noah gave out checks for rain.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>Towne—Groone doesn't take any interest in 
                    baseball. 
                    Downe—How do you know? 
                    Towne—He says he never allow himself to be- 
                    come angry or excited.</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>"I never had to throw up my job but once," said
                    a baseball umpire.  "It was a game between two 
                    deaf mute clubs. They kept so quiet about the
                    decisions that I got rattled before the fourth inning."</p>
                <milestone unit="line"/>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
                <p>One day the office-boy went to the editor of the 
                    Soaring Eagle and said, "There's a tramp at the 
                    door, and he says he has had nothing to eat for six 
                    days.' 
                    "Fetch him in," said the editor.  "If we can find 
                    out how he does it we can run this paper for an- 
                    other week."</p>
            </div>
            
                

                
                
                
                
                
                
                <pb n="56"/>
                <pb n="57"/>
                
                
                
                <pb n="61"/>
                <pb n="62"/>
                <pb n="63"/>
                <pb n="64"/>
                <pb n="65"/>
                <pb n="66"/>
                <pb n="67"/>
                <pb n="68"/>
                <pb n="69"/>
                <pb n="70"/>
                <pb n="71"/>
                <pb n="72"/>
                <pb n="73"/>
                <pb n="74"/>
                <pb n="75"/>
                <pb n="76"/>
                <pb n="77"/>
                <pb n="78"/>
                <pb n="79"/>
                <pb n="80"/>
                <pb n="81"/>
                <pb n="82"/>
                <pb n="83"/>
                <pb n="84"/>
                <pb n="85"/>
                <pb n="86"/>
                <pb n="87"/>
                <pb n="88"/>
                <pb n="89"/>
                <pb n="90"/>
                <pb n="91"/>
                <pb n="92"/>
                <pb n="93"/>
                <pb n="94"/>
                
                

               

           
        </body>
    </text>

</TEI>
